{
    "id": "0421243c95584afcaab94ae2baf044c6",
    "title": "Should and would",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "492fbf8b1f404ce3a5fbf2eedfc8fb4d",
            "title": "Should and Would | Grammar Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Everyone …………….. wear a helmet.",
                    "description": "We use should to show obligation. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "should",
                        "would"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "When we were kids we ……………… spend hours playing caroms.",
                    "description": "We use would to talk about past habits. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "should",
                        "would"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I told him that I ……………… probably be late.",
                    "description": "In American English, should is not normally possible here. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "would",
                        "should",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "We ……………….. be grateful for an early reply.",
                    "description": "Note that in American English, should is not normally used in this situation.",
                    "answers": [
                        "would",
                        "should",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………… I open the door?",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "Should",
                        "Would",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If we all sang in tune, it ………………. be so bad.",
                    "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would / could / might + infinitive in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "wouldn't",
                        "shouldn't"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………….. I turn the heating on?",
                    "description": "Should is used in polite inquiries. Would is used in polite requests. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Should",
                        "Would"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "………………. we invite Judy?",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "Should",
                        "Would"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "………………… you mind moving a bit?",
                    "description": "The expression 'would you mind' is a polite way of requesting someone to do something. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Would",
                        "Should"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She ……………… be informed.",
                    "description": "Should shows necessity. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "should",
                        "would",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}